Previously on the show.
Episode sebelumnya.
The goats ended up in Balloon City during a storm,
Para Kambing berakhir di Kota Balon saat badai,
and ran into Sparky who was a wanted figure.
dan bertemu Sparky yang sedang buron.
After failing to escape the storm,
Setelah gagal kabur dari badai,
they found that General Balloon, who was trying to capture Sparky,
ternyata Jenderal Balon, yang mencoba menangkap Sparky,
was actually Sparky's good friend.
sebenarnya teman baik Sparky.
What will happen to the goats while staying in Balloon City?
Bagaimana nasib para kambing saat tinggal di Kota Balon?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Beam That Makes You Strong And Tough."
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Sinar yang Membuatmu Kuat dan Tangguh.
You're all Sparky's friends.
Kalian teman Sparky.
Let me be a good host and show you our delicacies!
Aku akan jadi tuan rumah yang baik dan menyajikan hidangan lezat!
Wow, delicacies!
Wah, hidangan lezat!
This contains our most famous cuisine.
Ini berisi masakan paling terkenal.
Isn't our food delicious?
Bukankah makanan kami enak?
There is no food! It's just air!
Tak ada makanan. Itu hanya udara!
They are balloons,
Mereka adalah balon, jadi makan udara saja.
What do we eat then?
Lalu, kita makan apa?
Don't worry.
Tenang.
Rubbish bin?
Sampah?
They don't eat food.
Mereka tak makan.
So food caught in the storm
Jadi, makanan yang terbawa badai akan dibuang ke tong sampah.
Wow! There's so much delicious food!
Wah! Ada begitu banyak makanan lezat!
Sigh, you goats don't know how to appreciate our delicacies.
Kalian para kambing tak tahu cara menghargai makanan lezat kami.
Go in.
Masuklah.
Wolnie?
Wolnie?
Wolffy? You're finally here.
Wolffy? Akhirnya kau di sini.
Why are you guys here?
Mengapa kalian di sini?
That day...
Pada hari itu...
Wolffy!
Wolffy!
Wolnie, Willie! It was so dangerous! Are you hurt?
Wolnie, Willie! Itu sangat berbahaya! Apa kau terluka?
-Dad. -We are fine now.
- Ayah. - Kami tak apa-apa.
I'm glad you're both safe.
Senang kalian di sini.
Wolffy.
Wolffy.
Wolnie.
Wolnie.
I'm really touched at the sight of your family reunion.
Aku sangat tersentuh saat lihat reuni keluargamu.
But Sirius is too dangerous.
Tapi Sirius terlalu berbahaya.
We've confiscated it...
Kami menyitanya...
You confiscated Sirius?
Kau menyita Sirius?
Also, you destroyed our houses.
Kau pun menghancurkan rumah kami.
We have captured you so that you will clear the rubbish for us
Kami menangkapmu agar kau membereskan sampahnya
as compensation.
untuk kami.
You confiscated Sirius
Kau menyita Sirius
and you still expect me to clear your rubbish?
dan masih berharap aku beres-beres?
I, Wolffy, won't--
Aku, Wolffy, takkan...
Won't what?
Takkan apa?
Won't reject the idea.
Takkan menolak idenya.
Weslie, what new functions does the Magic Train have?
Weslie, fungsi baru apa yang dimiliki Kereta Ajaib?
We just need to put our palm mark on the new Magic Train
Kita hanya perlu taruh telapak tangan di Kereta Ajaib baru
to activate our respective abilities.
untuk mengaktifkan kemampuan.
That amazing?
Itu luar biasa?
Let's give it a try then.
Mari kita coba.
Is this my seat?
Apa ini kursiku?
Come on, try activating it with your palm mark.
Ayo, aktifkan dengan taruh telapak tanganmu.
Let's see what the function is.
Mari lihat apa fungsinya.
Start!
Mulai!
Good afternoon, goats.
Selamat siang, Kambing.
General Balloon!
Jenderal Balon!
I saw you come aboard Magic Train, so I came to take a look.
Kulihat kau naik ke Kereta Ajaib, jadi aku datang untuk melihat.
You didn't do anything dangerous, right?
Kau tak melakukan hal berbahaya, bukan?
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
That's good then. I'm leaving.
Bagus. Aku pergi.
Be careful, okay?
Hati-hati, ya?
General Balloon blocked our view just now.
Jenderal Balon menghalangi kita. Kita tak tahu apa kegunaan sinarnya.
And this button isn't lit up anymore.
Dan tombol ini tak menyala lagi.
That means the skill is cooling off.
Berarti ada jeda dahulu.
Let's try again later.
Kita coba lagi nanti.
We're done!
Selesai!
Son, there's still a lot more rubbish to clear.
Nak, masih banyak sampah yang harus dibersihkan.
Why's there so much rubbish here?
Kenapa ada banyak sampah di sini?
The storm is to blame.
Ini salah badainya.
Like all this stuff, we came from Earth.
Seperti semua ini, kami datang dari Bumi.
After being sucked into the storm,
Setelah tersedot ke dalam badai,
seeing that we can fly,
mengingat kami bisa terbang,
we gathered together to build Balloon City.
kami berkumpul untuk membangun Kota Balon.
For safety purposes, we built high walls.
Demi keamanan, kami membangun tembok tinggi.
But there're still many things that get blown into the city.
Tapi masih banyak hal yang tersedot masuk ke kota ini.
If there's too much rubbish in the city, we'll be pulled down to the ground.
Jika terlalu banyak sampah di kota, kami akan jatuh ke bawah.
So, our duty is to clear the rubbish in the city at all times.
Jadi, tugas kami adalah membersihkan sampah di kota.
I can't stand this weight either.
Aku juga tak tahan dengan berat ini.
Wolffy!
Wolffy!
Wolnie!
Wolnie!
It has cooled off.
Sudah selesai.
Let's try aiming it at the apple.
Mari kita coba di apel itu.
Good idea.
Ide bagus.
I found a fridge full of food.
Aku menemukan kulkas penuh makanan.
Start!
Mulai!
Look, everybody. I found a fridge full of food!
Semua, lihat! Aku menemukan kulkas penuh makanan!
Paddi! Move out of the way!
Paddi! Minggir!
What a big harvest!
Ini panen besar!
Nothing happened to me?
Aku kenapa?
Why has the fridge shrunk?
Kenapa kulkasnya menyusut?
It has also become very light.
Dan jadi sangat ringan.
It doesn't hurt at all.
Tadi tidak sakit.
What exactly is going on?
Apa yang sebenarnya terjadi?
It turns out that Sparky's skill is to make something strong and tough.
Keahlian Sparky adalah membuat sesuatu yang kuat dan tangguh.
I see!
Aku mengerti!
I'm back to normal.
Aku sudah normal.
So it only lasts for ten minutes.
Jadi hanya berlangsung selama sepuluh menit.
It's impossible to clear all the rubbish!
Mustahil membersihkan semua sampah!
I must find Sirius soon and take Wolnie and Willie away.
Aku harus segera temukan Sirius dan bawa Wolnie dan Willie.
Where are you going?
Kau mau ke mana?
I'm going to sweep every corner of this city.
Aku akan menyapu tiap sudut kota ini.
I must try and find out where Sirius is.
Aku harus mencari tahu di mana Sirius.
Balloon City is so small. Where do you hide big objects?
Kota Balon sangat kecil. Di mana kau menyembunyikan benda besar?
Why should I tell you?
Untuk apa kuberi tahu?
It's because you don't know, right?
Jadi kau tak tahu, bukan?
Of course I know!
Tentu aku tahu!
This is the giant goods warehouse. Big enough, huh?
Ini gudang barang raksasa. Cukup besar, ya?
I don't mean this.
Bukan ini.
I want to go to the place where vehicles are kept.
Aku mau ke tempat di mana kendaraan disimpan.
I see.
Aku mengerti.
Garage, boatyard, hangar.
Garasi, galangan kapal, hanggar.
There are so many planes.
Ada banyak pesawat.
I can take Wolnie away from here.
Aku bisa bawa Wolnie menjauh dari sini.
But these are only models.
Tapi ini hanya model.
I guess I must be explicit.
Kurasa aku harus lebih jelas.
Actually, I want to know where Sirius is.
Sebenarnya, aku mau tahu di mana Sirius berada.
Turn left at the intersection ahead and you'll see it.
Kiri di persimpangan, kau akan lihat.
Wow! There's a flying saucer!
Wah! Ada piring terbang.
That isn't a flying saucer!
Itu bukan piring terbang!
It's clearly a huge rock!
Itu jelas batu besar!
Emergency! A huge meteorite will hit Balloon City within ten minutes.
Darurat! Meteorit besar akan menghantam Kota Balon dalam 10 menit.
Please take necessary precautions to avoid the impact.
Mohon coba untuk menghindarinya.
What should we do?
Kita harus bagaimana?
Calm down, everybody!
Tenang, Semua! Bukankah ada sinar yang buat orang kuat?
We can just use it to turn one of us into a giant and knock the meteorite away.
Kita pakai itu untuk berubah jadi raksasa lalu pukul meteoritnya.
Then I must do it. I have the experience.
Akan kulakukan. Aku berpengalaman.
Si... rius?
Sirius?
This isn't Sirius!
Ini bukan Sirius!
So Magic Train is parked here.
Kereta Ajaib parkir di sini.
Isn't that...
Bukankah itu...
Just let me save everybody.
Aku akan menolong semuanya.
A goat?
Kambing?
Let me catch a few goats before locating Sirius.
Aku akan menangkap kambing sebelum mencari Sirius.
Oh, no. Wolffy got hit by the strong beam.
Gawat. Wolffy terkena sinar kuat!
He's strong and tough now.
Dia jadi kuat dan tangguh.
He's gonna eat us all.
Dia akan memakan kita semua.
I've become strong and tough.
Aku sudah menjadi kuat dan tangguh.
Now I'm powerful.
Sekarang, aku kuat.
Nothing can stop me from catching the goats now.
Kini aku mudah menangkap kambing.
Wolffy!
Wolffy!
Wolffy, you've been smirking for the past nine and a half minutes.
Wolffy, kau sudah menyeringai selama 9,5 menit.
Your ability will be gone in thirty seconds.
Kemampuanmu akan hilang dalam 30 detik.
Thirty seconds is enough time for me to catch you all.
Itu cukup untuk menangkap kalian.
Wolffy? Is this the time to think about catching goats?
Wolffy? Apa Ini waktu untuk menangkap kambing?
Look up!
Lihat ke atas!
What?
Ada apa?
Wolffy, while you're still strong and tough, knock the rock away.
Wolffy, selagi kau masih kuat, pukul batu itu.
The meteorite will hit the city in ten seconds.
Meteorit itu akan menghantam dalam sepuluh detik.
Wolffy, go for it.
Wolffy, kau bisa!
Dad, go for it.
Ayah, kau bisa.
Go for it...
Kau bisa...
That's easier said than done.
Ini tak semudah itu juga.
There are four more seconds! Three!
Empat detik lagi? Tiga!
Go for it!
Kau bisa!
-Two! -Go for it!
- Dua! - Kau bisa!
One!
Satu!
He did it!
Dia berhasil!
Great!
Bagus!
Sparky's ability is awesome.
Kemampuan Sparky luar biasa.
Let's find a way to break through the storm now.
Kini mari cari cara menembus badainya.
Before we break through the storm, let's escape from Wolffy first!
Sebelum menembus badai, ayo kabur dari Wolffy!
I helped you get rid of the rock.
Aku membantumu menyingkirkan batu itu.
Let me eat you! Stop!
Biarkan aku memakanmu. Berhenti!
Does it really last for only ten minutes?
Itu hanya tahan sepuluh menit?
Let's cheer for the hero!
Mari bersorak untuk pahlawan!
Wolffy, thank you for saving us. What a happy day!
Wolffy, terima kasih. Ini hari yang bahagia!
We must celebrate.
Kita harus merayakannya.
You've destroyed our houses!
Kalian merusak rumah kami!
Sorry, we'll continue with tidying up!
Maaf, kami akan terus merapikannya!
TO BE CONTINUED 2759 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
BERSAMBUNG 2.759 HARI SEBELUM PULANG